Hello, and welcome to Lesson 24 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好 欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第24课
The topic of this lesson is the definite integral.
本节课的课题是定积分
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
先来简单介绍一下本课的内容
In the previous lesson, we talked about the Riemann sum
在上一节课中 我们讲了黎曼和
and the limit of said sum for a function f[x].
以及所述和的极限为函数 f[x]
Usually we picked f to be positive, and if we did that,
通常我们选择 f 是正的 如果我们这样做
then one could interpret the sum as being
那么和就可以解释为
the area under the curve corresponding to f.
与 f 对应的曲线下的面积
But there is a slight problem to this approach
但这种做法有一个小小的问题
because the Riemann sum has lots of practical applications,
因为黎曼和有很多实际应用
such as finding the area under the velocity curve.
如求速度曲线下的面积
Here’s an example.
这里有一个例子
That’s the velocity of a particle, let’s say.
这就是粒子的速度
Here’s a plot.
请看这个图
Then the area under this curve can be interpreted as
那么这条曲线下的面积可以解释为
the total distance traveled by the particle,
粒子走过的总距离
in this case from 0 to 5 seconds, let’s say.
在这种情况下 从 0 到 5 秒
Now the question is what happens if f is negative?
现在的问题是 如果 f 是负数会怎样
After all, the velocity of a particle can be
毕竟 一个粒子的速度可以根据方向不同
either positive or negative depending upon the direction.
可以是正的 也可以是负的
That’s the question that we want to answer in this lesson,
这就是我们这节课要回答的问题
and then we will talk about some properties of the Riemann sum.
然后我们再来谈谈黎曼和的一些特性
Let’s begin with a definition.
先说说定义
Because we use Riemann sums so often,
因为我们经常使用黎曼和
we have given it a special name in mathematics.
我们在数学上给它起了一个特殊的名字
It’s called the definite integral.
这就是所谓的定积分
In fact, there is also a special notation
其实还有一个特殊的记号
for that rather cumbersome Riemann sum.
对于那个相当繁琐的黎曼和
It’s just called integral from a to b f(x)d(x).
从 a 到 bf(x)d(x) 就叫积分。
That over there, that elongated S, is the definite integral sign
在那边 那个拉长的 S 就是定积分的符号
with a and b, the limits, at both the ends.
以 a 和 b 为极限 在两端
The S over here, like I said,
这里的S就像我说的
is just the elongated S standing for “sum”.
只是加长的 S 代表 "和"
When you find the area under a function curve from a to b,
当你找到从 a到b 的函数曲线下的面积时
we’ll say that we are integrating the function from a to b.
我们将说我们正在整合函数从 a 到 b
Luckily the Wolfram Language has
幸运的是 Wolfram语言有
a very nice built-in function that integrates these functions,
一个非常好的内置函数 整合了这些功能
and it’s called Integrate.
而它的名字叫 Integrate
Integrate is the function that you’d use
Integrate 是你要使用的函数
to compute these definite integrals.
来计算这些定积分
For example, let’s look at f[x] = x^2, and you want to integrate,
例如 我们看 f[x]=x^2 你想求积分
let’s say, from 0 to 1.
比方说 从 0 到 1
Here’s a Riemann sum and the limit, and you get back the answer 1/3.
这里有一个黎曼和和极限 你得到的答案是 1/3
But you could just as well use
但你也可以用
the Integrate symbol that’s over here.
在这里的 Integrate 符号
You integrate from 0 to 1 for x^2,
你对 x^2 从 0 到 1 进行积分
and you get back just the same answer, 1/3.
而你得到的只是同样的答案 1/3
Integrate is the function to use
Integrate 当你想定义积分时
when you want to do definite integration.
是要使用的功能
Now, the point is that not every function is integrable.
现在问题的关键是不是每个函数都是可可积的
Not every function can be integrated, and that’s because
并不是每个函数都能做积分 因为
the limit in the Riemann sum may not converge to a finite value.
黎曼和中的极限可能不会收敛到一个有限值
Here’s an example.
有一个例子
You have f[x] = 1/x and you’re trying to find the integral.
你想找 f[x]=1/x 的积分
Notice over here I’m using the full text over here for Integrate
请注意 我在这里使用的是 Integrate 的全称
rather than the symbol, and it says over here that this integral
而不是符号 这边说的是这个积分
does not converge on 0 to 1, and that’s because
不会在 0 到 1 之间收敛 这是因为
the graph shows that in fact you have an ∞ near 0
从图中可以看出 实际上你的 ∞ 接近 0
because 1/x becomes infinite as you approach 0 from the right.
因为当你从右边接近 0 时 1/x 会变得无限大
Luckily in this lesson, we’ll talk about
幸运的是 在这节课中 我们会讲到一些函数
functions which can be integrated as long as you’re careful.
只要你细心 就能积分
In general, one has the property that a function is integrable
一般来说 我们有这样的性质 一个函数如果它是连续的或者在图形中没有断裂
if it is continuous—no breaks in the graph—
则是可积分的
or it has only a finite number of jump discontinuities.
或者它只有有限的跳跃不连续的数
In this case, the point is you actually have
在这种情况下
an infinite discontinuity at 0, and that’s a real problem.
实际上在0处有无限的不连续性 这是一个真正的问题。
Okay. Let’s go on now to talking about functions which have
好了 现在我们继续讨论一下有哪些函数
a negative function value.
有负函数值
For example, you have the function f[x] = –x,
例如 你有函数 f[x] = -x
and you want find its area.
而你想找到它的面积
Well the point is because it’s negative,
好吧 关键是因为它是负的
what you do is you find the area from 0 to 1
你要做的是找到 0 到 1 的面积
as if it’s a normal triangle that’s 1/2,
仿佛是一个正常的三角形 是 1/2
and then you get the minus sign, and you get the answer, –1/2.
然后你得到负号 你得到的答案 -1/2
if you use integrate, you get back just the same result,
如果你使用积分 你会得到同样的结果
–1/2, for this integral.
对于这个积分是 -1/2
Okay. Next point over here is what happens if you have a function
好的 下一个问题是如果你有一个既是正数也是负数的函数
which is both positive and negative.
会发生什么
Let’s take a sine function.
就拿正弦函数来说吧
Now we see what happens over here is that the function is
现在我们看到这里 如函数是有时是正的 有时是负的
sometimes positive and sometimes negative.
会发生什么
It’s positive from 0 to π, and then negative from π to 2π.
从 0 到 π 是正数 然后从 π 到 2π 是负数
In this case, what you’ll do is you’ll add
在这种情况下 你要做的是添加
all the areas above the x axis
所有在 x 轴上方的面积
and then you subtract the sum of the areas below the x axis,
然后减去 x 轴下的面积之和
and you get back the net area.
你就会得到净面积
Now in this case, of course, we have a positive area
在这种情况下 我们有一个正的区域和负面积
and a negative area, and the net area is 0.
净面积为 0
Let’s check that over here with Integrate,
让我们用 Integrate 函数检查一下
and you do get back the answer is 0 for this area.
而这个区域你确实得到的答案是的 0
Okay. On to some properties of definite integrals.
好吧 那就说说定积分的一些特性
If you work out the integral from a to b of a function,
如果你计算出一个函数从 a 到 b 的积分
then that’s the negative of the area from b to a.
那么这就是从 b 到 a 负值区域
For example, if you work out the integral of x^2 from 1 to 0,
例如 如果你计算出 x^2 从 1 到 0 的积分
that’s the negative of the area from 0 to 1,
这是从 0 到 1 的负值区域
so you have a –1/3 over here and 1/3 over there.
所以你有一个 -1/3 在这里和 1/3 在那里
In particular, if a = b, then you have
特别是 如果 a=b 然后你有
something which is negative itself, so the area in this case
本身就是负数的函数 所以如果这里的面积只是 0
is just 0, and that makes sense
那就有意义了
because there’s no area between a and a to compute.
因为在 a 和 a 之间没有区域可以计算
In our particular case, if you take the integral of f from 1 to 1,
在我们的特殊情况下 如果你把 f 的积分从 1 到 1
then you get back 0 as expected.
那么就会得到 0
Okay. Properties two.
好的，下面说性质二
You see over here that if you have a constant function
看这里 如果有一个常数函数
and you find the integral from a to b,
并找到从 a 到 b 的积分
then you just get back the constant value times (b – a).
那么你只需取回常量然后乘以 （b-a）
If you have a sum of functions, then the integral is
如果你有一个函数之和 那么积分是
the sum of f integral and the g integral.
f 的积分之和 以及 g 积分之和
For a difference, the integral of f – g
对于一个差值 f-g 的积分是
is the integral of f minus the integral of g.
f 的积分减去 g 的积分
Finally, you can always pull out constants
最后 你可以随时调出常量
from inside integral signs and save yourself some computation.
从积分符号里面 省去一些计算
For the first property, for example, if you want to find
对于第一个性质 举个例子
the area from, let’s say, 1 to 5 for the function
如果你想找的是函数从1到5一个区域
with constant height 5, then the answer is just going to be 20.
高度恒定是5 那么答案就是 20。
After all, you have 5 times 4, which is equal to 20.
毕竟 你有 5 乘以 4 等于 20
Okay. The final set of properties is that
好吧 最后一组性质是
if you have three points a, b and c
如果你有三点 a b c
and you want to work out the area from a to c,
你要计算出从 a 到 c 的的面积
you work out the integral from a to b and then b to c,
你计算出从 a 到 b 的积分，然后从 b 到 c
and you get back the area from a to c.
最后你得到的区域从 a 到 c
Now obviously if a function is non-negative,
现在很明显 如果一个函数是非负数的
then the area also will be non-negative,
那么该区域也将是非负数
and if f is larger than g, then the integral of of f
而如果 f 大于 g 则 f 的积分为
will be larger than the integral of g.
将大于 g 的积分
One last point: if f is kind of sandwiched between
最后一点：如果f之间夹杂着
the limits m and the capital M over here,
这里的界限 m 和大写的 m
then the area for f will be sandwiched between the area
那么 f 的区域将被夹在以下区域之间
for a rectangle with sides m(b – a)
边长为m(b-a)的矩形
and a larger rectangle with sides M(b – a).
和一个较大的矩形 边长为M(b-a)
Here’s a picture.
这里有一张图
That’s the function f, and the area under f
这就是函数 f 以及 f 下的面积
is sandwiched between the areas of those two rectangles.
被夹在这两个矩形的区域之间
That brings me to the end of this lesson.
本课到这里就结束了
To summarize, we have given a new name to Riemann sums.
综上所述 我们给黎曼和起了一个新的名字
You now call them definite integrals.
你现在称它们为定积分
These definite integrals have many nice special properties
这些定积分有许多很好的特殊性质
which makes them easy to compute.
这使得它们易于计算
The nice thing about the definite integral is it can handle
定积分的好处是它可以处理
functions with both positive values and negative values,
正值和负值的函数
and then you might get answers which are positive
然后你可能会得到正的答案
or negative or even 0.
或负的答案甚至是 0
We have a very nice function in the Wolfram Language
我们在 Wolfram 语言中有一个非常好的函数
which does the work for you.
可以为你运算
It’s called Integrate, and that is
它的名字叫 Integrate
a very popular, well-used function in the language.
它是一个在语言中非常流行的 很好用的函数
In the next lesson we’ll talk about
下一节课我们将讲到
the so-called fundamental theorem of calculus,
所谓微积分基本定理
which connects the two branches of calculus,
它连接了微积分的两个分支
integral calculus and differential calculus, together.
积分微积分和微分微积分
But before we do that, do review this lesson, go over the exercises
但在这之前 要先复习一下这节课
and be ready for the fundamental theorem of calculus.
并为微积分的基本定理做好准备
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
谢谢您今天就到这里吧
翻译 彭彦鸿